SUBIN LAL S.M.

Civil Engineer & Admin

- 🔀 lalsubin3@gmail.com 📞 +91 822011 5933 🛗 26 Aug 1995
- **♣** R7230251 **◎** Single **▶** Indian
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/subin-lal-s-m-837259142/
- https://github.com/subin-95



PROFILE

An organised and motivated individual looking to leverage my problem-solving skills build upon my 4+ years of site and project management experience by transitioning into software field .Looking for a challenging position to utilize & improve my strengths and abilities in the mentioned field.

SKILLS

- Project Management
- Excel
- Microsoft Office
- Office Administration
- source code management

- Team Management
- Organizational Skills.
- Planning & Excecution
- Sourcing and screening resumes
- wordpress

- Auto CADD (2D)
- JAVA (developing)
- SQL (devloping)
- procurement
- HTML & CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Admin & Site Manager

ESS ESS BUILDERS

- Assisted employees as needed and resolved benefit issues.
- Provided problem resolutions to employee inquiries and employee relation issues Assisted with benefits
- Supported the maintenance of employee records, filing select paperwork and serving as backup support for routine filing.
- Managed new hire employee paperwork, created employee file and entered deductions and withholdings into payroll system.

Civil Site Engineer

OTHMAN SALEH AL GHAMDI TRADING &

CONTRACTING CO.

- Perform and coordinate inspections and determine quality assurance testing models of raw materials and finished products.
- Prepare, document, and execute detailed test plans, test cases, and defect reports.

Jul 2019 - Nov 2021 Dammam, Saudi Arabia

Jan 2022 - present

- Worked in HR Team by sourcing and screeing resumes and doing basic interviews and managing employees files.
- Worked in Admin Team and procurement Team in Covid times.
- Conduct daily site inspection, monitor, safety implementation and supervision.
- Develop and initiate quality standards for tests, inspections and evaluations

Junior Civil Engineer

Jun 2017 - Jun 2019 | Nagercoil, India

CHRIS CONSTRUCTION & CONSULTANTS

- Creating work schedule, work assignment to the staff and periodic reports.
- Ensured that the constructions procedure is in alignment with rules.
- Wrote daily reports for accountability and quality assurance.
- Analyzing & Evaluating all Work and performance.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree in Civil Engineering

2013 - 2017 | chennai, India

Sathyabama University

High Secondary Certificate

2013 | Marthandam, India

Christhuraja Higher Secondary School

CERTIFICATES

Certification of Java & Sql

ICT Academy (pursuing)

Business Analysis & Process Management

Coursera - 2022

Master Diploma in Project Planning & Management

Synergy School of business skills - 2019

Professional in Building Design

CADD Centre -2017.

- Business Administrative
- Project Management
- Business operations

- web development
- Java

♠ LANGUAGES

English • • • • Tamil • • • • • • Malayalam • • • • • • Arabic